Mss.B.W84 Mss.B.W84
American Philosophical Society
George B. (George Bacon) Wood papers, 1815-1913
Mss.B.W84
American Philosophical Society
30.0 Item(s)
These papers include correspondence concerning the publication and republication of Wood's "Dispensatory of the United States" and "Treatise on Therapeutics and Pharmacology, or Materia Medica" by J.B. Lippincott Co. Also included are twelve diplomas and certificates of membership in American and European professional societies.
30 items.
Wood, George B.(George Bacon),1797-1879.
Box 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased and accessioned, 1949.
Biographical/Historical note
George Bacon Wood was a Philadelphia physician, and was elected to the American Philosophical Society in 1829.
Early American History Note
The George Bacon Wood collection consists primarily of correspondence from George Wood to J.B. Lippincott. Some of the letters are co-signed by Franklin Bache. All of the letters date from 1860 onwards. The only early American materials are various diplomas and certificates from the 1810s and 1820s for Wood. These include a diploma from the University of Pennsylvania and the Philadelphia College of Pharmacy, and various certificates from places like the Philomathean Society at Penn and medical societies.
Beyond Early America; Certificates.; Diplomas.; Educational Material; Institutional Records; Medicine; Medicine.; Pharmacology.
- Series One: Papers
  - Letter to J. B. Lippincott, Nov. 5, 1863; 10x8; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Scope and Contents note
    A.L.S.: Geo.B.Wood and Franklin Bache. 1p.and add. (see G.B.Wood papers.No.1.) Accepts his proposal to publish their U.S. Dispensatory.
  - Letter to J. B. Lippincott Co., Aug. 10, 1867; 7-1/2x5-1/4; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No.2.) Accepts proposal for printing additional copies of U.S.Dispensatory.
  - Statement of accounts to Geo[rge] B. Wood, Nov. 8, 1867; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Lippincott, J. B., Co.
    Philadelphia, D. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No.3.) Lists copies of his work sent to various persons and institutions, including the APS.
  - Statement that George B. Wood, MD., President of the American Philosophical Society, etc., copyrights a book, Nov. 9, 1867; 14x8-1/2; Library of Congress. Copyright office
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: John B. Beaver, Clerk District Court. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers, No. 4.)
  - Letter to J. B.Lippincott, Co., Philadelphia, Nov. 11, 1867; 10x8; Library of Congress
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p. Duplicate. (see G.B.Wood papers. No. 5) Thanks for publication by Wood.
  - Receipt to J. B. Lippincott, Co. for copyright for his book, Nov. 20, 1867; 3-1/4x8; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, D. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No.6.)
  - Letter to J. B. Lippincott, Jan. 9, 1868; 8x5; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 7.) Accepts his proposal to print a new edition of his Dispensatory.
  - Receipt to J.B.Lippincott for copyright for his Dispensatory, June 8, 1868; 7x4-1/2; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 8.)
  - Letter to J. B. Lippincott Company, March 2, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 9.) Accepts proposal for their printing his Therapeutics.
  - Letter to J. B. Lippincott Company, Dec. 24, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    A.L.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 10.) Concerning a reprinting of his Dispensatory.
  - Letter to J. B. Lippincott Company, July 7, 1877; 8x5; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers No. 11.) Accepts conditions for reprinting his Dispensatory.
  - Agreement with the Committee of the revision and publication of the U.S. Pharmacopoeia to quote what is needed in the U.S. Dispensatory..., Feb. 24, 1880; 9-1/4x6; Lippincott, J. B., Co.
    D. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 12.)
  - Minute, Feb. 24, 1883; 9x8; National College of Pharmacy (Washington, D.C.). Committee of National College of Pharmacy on the U.S. Pharmacopoeia
    Boston, Mass., D. 1p. Extract. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 13.) Agreement that J.B.Lippincott may quote from publication.
  - Receipt to J. B. Lippincott Company for full payment due the estate of George B. Wood, Feb. 6, 1885; 4-1/4x8; Wood, Anna E.
    D.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 14.)
  - Letter to [Joshua] Bert[ram Lippincott], Jan. 26, 1910; 11x8-1/2; Wood, H. C. (Horatio C.), 1841-1920
    Typed L.S. 2p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 15.) Asks for bust of G.B.Wood, presented to J.B.Lippincott, for the College of Physicians.
  - Letter to J. Bertram Lippincott, Jan. 28, 1910; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Wood, H. C. (Horatio C.), 1841-1920
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see G.B.Wood papers. No. 16.) Thanks for the gift of the G.B.Wood bust to the College of Physicians.
  - Letter to J. Bertram Lippincott, Jan. 27, 1912; 11x8-1/2; Remington, Joseph P. (Joseph Price), 1847-1918
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see G. B. Wood papers. No. 17.) Has ideas he would like to discuss for furthering medical publications from Lippincott..
  - Letter to [Joshua] Bert[ram Lippincott], Feb. 4, 1913; 10-1/2x8; Wood, H. (Horatio C.), 1841-1920
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 2p. (see G.B. Wood papers. No. 18.) Concerning future policy on publication
- Series Two: Certificates and diplomas, 1815-1871; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
  D. 12 items. Various sizes.
  - Diploma issued to George B. Wood, January 5, 1815; 19 1/2" x 15"; University of Pennsylvania
    Parchment D.S. by faculty. 1p. In Latin. Seal. (Certificates no.1.)
  - Certificate issued to George B. Wood, January 10, 1815; 18" x 16"; University of Pennsylvania. Philomathean Society
    Parchment D. S. by officers. In Latin. ( Certificates no. 2.)
  - Diploma issued to George B. Wood, April 10, 1818; 24" x 20 1/2"; University of Pennsylvania
    Philadelphia, Parchment D.S. by the faculty. 1p. In Latin. Seal. ( Certificates no.3.) M.D. degree.
  - Certificate of membership issued to George B. Wood, February 22, 1825; 14" x 10"; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    D.S. by officers. 1p. (Certificates no.4.)
  - Certificate issued to George B. Wood, Jan. 4, 1827; 19-1/2x23; University of Pennsylvania. Philomathean Society
    Parchment D.S.by officers. 1p. In Latin. ( Certificates no.5.)
  - Certificate of membership issued to George B. Wood, April 10, 1827; 16" x 12"; College of Physicians of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Parchment D.S. by officers. 1p. In Latin. Seal. ( Certificates no.6.)
  - Certificate of membership issued to George B. Wood, February 24, 1829; 12" x 14 1/2"; Philadelphia College of Pharmacy
    D.S. by officers. 1p. (Certificates no. 7.)
  - Certificate issued to George B. Wood, June 26, 1839; 14 1/2" x 15 1/2"; Rhode Island Medical Society
    Providence, D.S. by officers. 1p. In Latin. Seal. ( Certificates no.8.)
  - Certificate issued to George B. Wood, October 3, 1854; 11 1/2" x 13"; Massachusetts Medical Society
    Boston, Parchment D.S. by officers. 1p. In Latin. Seal. (Certificates no.9.)
  - Certificate issued to George B. Wood, November 20, 1862; 22" x 16"; Accademia de' Quiriti
    D.S. by officers. 1p. In Italian. ( Certificates no.10.)
  - Certificate issued to Georges Wood making him a "Membre Correspondant Étrangeres", May 2, 1866; 13x17-1/4; Société de pharmacie de Paris
    D.S.by officers. 1p. Parchment. In French. ( Certificates no.11.)
  - Certificate issued to George B. Wood, April 20, 1871; 18" x 23"; New York Academy of Medicine
    D.S. by officers 1p. In Latin. (Certificates no.12.)